Heitor Gouvêa

Cybersecurity Researcher and Speaker

SUMMARY

I have been working on projects that help people, organizations and companies take control of their own informations. My work is focused on understanding threat models, analyzing existing applications and building intelligent tools to combat risk current and future security for both individuals or groups.

I have audited high profile websites for security vulnerabilities and have managed and worked in teams of software developers and computer scientists delivering high security architectures.

I like information security and software development, particularly in the areas of secure protocols, cryptography, privacy, and anonymity. But I also secretly hate technology.

On my profile on Github you can see some of my codes written during my researches: https://github.com/GouveaHeitor

EXPERIENCE

Cybersecurity Researcher

04/2018 - PRESENT

Bugcrowd Inc

I work remotely by participating in public and private Bug Bounty Hunting programs, researching vulnerabilities in certain partner companies.

Security and Development Analyst

11/2017 - 03/2018

Horizon Four

I acted providing consulting in the field of information security offensive to institutions, private companies and governmental organizations. My work was focused on writing business proposal models, confidentiality and reports, and understanding threat models, analyzing existing applications and building intelligent tools to combat current and future security risk for both individuals or groups.

Information Technology Trainee

04/2016 - 11/2017

IMA - Computer Associates Municipalities S/A

I participated in the trainee program in order to be trained and prepared to assume strategic positions in the future. During the trainee process I worked directly with clients understanding their problems and later proposing some solutions, developing, performing vulnerability analyzes and maintaining Government Systems that used technologies like: PHP 7, Symfony Framework, JavaScript, CoffeeScript, Doctrine, MySQL, Twig, Ruby On Rails and others technologies.

EDUCATION

Offensive Information Security Grade Autodidact

Self-Educated

Because I did not fit into the traditional teaching model, I opted to continue studying independently after completing the high school. I started my studies in the field of Information Security Offensive in 2015 and since then I have been studying about: software development, from engineering to computer science, networks and computer systems, vulnerability analysis, pentesting, cryptography, cryptanalysis, anonymity and privacy.

Santa Rita do Sapucaí, Minas Gerais, Brazil

(19) 991 891 355 hi@heitorgouvea.me

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Network: TCP/IP, UDP, HTTP, FTP, SSH, SMTP and Telnet

Architecture: Scalability, Distributed system, Decentralized systems, High architecture, Parallel computing and Design patterns

Front-end: HTML5, CSS3, MaterializeCSS, Sass, JavaScript and AngularJS

Back-end: Shell Script, Perl and Mojo Framework

Database: MySQL and PostgreSQL

Tools: Bower, Git, Npm, Jekyll, Grunt and Docker

Application Security:
Hardening, Cryptography,
Cryptanalysis, Vulnerability
analysis, Penetration
testing and Secure code
review

Agile Methods: Scrum and Extreme Programming

Others: Web performance, SEO, Responsive Design, Cross-browser, OOP, UML, Progressive Web Apps and Linux Administration

LANGUAGES

Portuguese: native proficiency

English: limited working proficiency